<resources>
<string name="app_name">scrollpractice</string>
<string name="scrolltext">
        10 Habits Of Highly Successful People
Jan 30, 2020, 6 mins read


The people you admire who have it figured out aren’t smarter than you. Instead, they’ve cultivated practices that make success ‘inevitable’. You can do the same with the help of these ten, simple-to-apply habits.

1. Cultivate good habits
“Depending on what they are, our habits will either make us or break us. We become what we repeatedly do.” ―Sean Covey

First things, first! The more ‘helpful’ activities you’re able to do on autopilot, the more successful you’ll become. Here’s why…

As creatures of habit, we do a lot of things without thinking. These well-worn patterns are just part of who we are. A habit takes minimal bandwidth or motivation because you do it automatically. That’s why habits are your secret weapon for stellar success.

The trick is to get clear on the habits that will move the needle on your life. Work, personal, or relationships, figure out the daily [and weekly actions] that will make all the difference, then use a tool such as the Habit Roadmap to make these habits stick.

Take the right actions consistently, and success becomes ‘inevitable’.

2. Gratitude
“Whether you think you can or you think you can’t, you’re right.” - Henry Ford

Success is as much mindset as it is a skill. If you believe you can do it, there’s a strong chance you’ll inspire yourself to get results. If you doubt yourself, your Reticular Activating System [or RAS for short] will consistently look for evidence to prove you’re right.

Successful people know how to cultivate positivity - and gratitude is one of the most powerful ways to do this. When you focus on what you do have, it’s harder for scarcity to creep in. When you feel abundant, it’s easier to go after the things you want.

That’s why so many successful people practice gratitude. Simply make a note of three things you’re grateful for everyday, and overtime, see how this influences your positive thinking.

3. Mindfulness
“Surrender to what is. Let go of what was. Have faith in what will be.” - Sonia Ricotti

The road to success won’t ever be smooth. There will be ups and downs - the question is, can you ride the storms as comfortably as you ride the highs?

MIndfulness is about finding your inner peace amongst the outer chaos. It’s about being fully present with what is - rather than resisting reality and wishing it were somehow different.

Mindfulness is an important habit to cultivate because it helps you accept present circumstances - so you can more effectively manage stress and anxiety. In turn, mindful people are better equipped to keep an even keel when the going gets tough.

Headspace has some incredible meditations to help you cultivate mindfulness - here’s a one-minute meditation to get you started.

4. Thrive in discomfort
“You can choose courage or you can choose comfort. You cannot have both.” - Brene Brown.

Success lies at the edge of your comfort zone. It exists in the space where you do the things you didn’t think you were capable of doing. It’s the result of considerate risk-taking and stretch goal setting.

Successful people are willing to thrive in discomfort. They’re happy to put themselves into situations when they don’t have all the answers and all the skills. They’re willing to overcome fear so they can be their best.

This takes courage and self-belief - something you can develop with practice.

So make it a habit to put courage over comfort - and see how much further you can go.

5. Default to action
“Do you want to know who you are? Don’t ask. Act! Action will delineate and define you.”
- Thomas Jefferson.

Ideas are one thing, but results happen when you’re willing to take action.

Successful people get stuff done. They step up to the plate. They don’t overthink to the point of confusion and overwhelm. Instead, they act on their plans to make the intangible a reality.

Make daily action towards your goals a habit and success becomes inevitable. You can use the Self Journal to inspire this.

6. Budget time
“The key is in not spending time, but in investing it.” - Stephen R. Covey.

Lack of time is often touted as the reason we can’t do the things we want.

But the truth is, we all have the same 1,440 minutes a day. It’s not a question of the amount of time, but how you use your time that counts.

This is why successful people plan their day with the same scrutiny they budget money. Be more mindful of where your minutes go. Look to see where procrastination and distractions take your time and steal your success potential.

Get into the habit of using a daily planner so you can leverage time to its max.

Implement techniques and practices that help you get more done in less time, and success becomes easier to create.

7. Journaling
"A personal journal is an ideal environment in which to become. It is a perfect place for you to think, feel, discover, expand, remember, and dream." - Brad Wilcox.

Daily journaling can create a gateway to your subconscious, your limiting beliefs, and your stretch goals.

When you write to make your inner thoughts and feelings tangible, you can process your emotions, make sense of events, and create the clarity you need to move forward confidently.

Journaling helps you to better know yourself - so you’re better equipped to succeed on your best self journey. Discover how to start journaling here.

8. Make better decisions.
“It is in your moments of decision that your destiny is shaped.” - Tony Robbins

Your life is a series of decisions - some conscious, some habitual, some fear-based. Every time you make a decision, you direct your life down a certain path.

Even the decision to NOT make a decision is still a decision!

Successful people are able to navigate the tough choices through life. This doesn’t mean they always get it right! Instead, they have the ability to be decisive - so they don’t stagnant or run around in circles.

It’s not always easy choosing the path ahead, but ask yourself the right question, and you can choose your preferred option with more confidence. Tools such as the Decision Deck can help with this.

9. Accountability
“At the end of the day we are accountable to ourselves - our success is a result of what we do.” - Catherine Pulsifer

It’s easy to say you’re going to do something.

But often a whole lot harder to actually do the thing! Fear, self-doubt, procrastination, distraction, second-guessing - so many factors can get in the way of making an idea a reality.

This is why successful people practice the habit of accountability - to themselves and other people.

When you know someone else is checking in on you, you’re more likely to get the work done. You can leverage the same tool yourself. The monthly Accountability Challenge in the BestSelf Alliance is a great place to start - and it’s free.

10. Reflection
“You cannot have a meaningful life without having self-reflection.” —Oprah Winfrey

Life has something to teach you every day. A new methodology, a different way of thinking, what works and what doesn’t - you name it. Reflection is the ultimate short-cut. When we’re able to learn from our own experiences, we can avoid making the same mistakes again and find success quicker.

Daily reflection needn’t be complicated or time-consuming.

Simply check in with yourself on a daily basis to see what you’ve learned that day. Also, collect your wins - so you can learn from those too.

Take a conscious approach to your every day life, and success will be easier to come by.

Success is different for everyone

While the principles of success are universal, success itself looks different for everyone.

So make sure you’re chasing your own version. Don’t get distracted and side-tracked by what other people say you should have, do, or be. Instead, focus on what YOU want to create for your life.

Then leverage the habits outlined in this article to get there.
    </string>
</resources>